<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code on Niall Martin</title>
    <link>https://niallmartin.io/tags/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code on Niall Martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://niallmartin.io/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Data Analysis] Dublin Property Trends</title>
      <link>https://niallmartin.io/posts/data-analysis-dublin-property-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niallmartin.io/posts/data-analysis-dublin-property-trends/</guid>
      <description>Analyse and Map Property Price Trends Looking for a house can be stressful. Where to go, what to spend, where the competition is. There&#39;s a lot of choice, but little analysis of the market as a whole.
As such, I spent the day reviewing data from the Property Price Register - a live dataset of all residential properties purchased in Ireland since the 1st January 2010. With information relating to the date of sale, sale price, and the address, this dataset provided me with enough base information to obtain the geospatial coordinates for all house sales using the Google Maps API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Colab Notebook] Keras &amp; LSTM models to Predict Stock Prices</title>
      <link>https://niallmartin.io/posts/colab-notebook-keras-lstm-models-to-predict-stock-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niallmartin.io/posts/colab-notebook-keras-lstm-models-to-predict-stock-prices/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing and Predicting Stock Market Trends</title>
      <link>https://niallmartin.io/posts/analysing-and-predicting-stock-market-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niallmartin.io/posts/analysing-and-predicting-stock-market-trends/</guid>
      <description>Aim This notebook aims to provide a brief outline the results from a stock-market analysis, demonstrating how LSTM RNN models can be implemented with Keras and Tensorflow. It&#39;s important to note that all results discussed in this post are intended to be high-level, though the reader is encouraged to review this colab notebook for a more detailed analysis and a discussion of the underlying code.
Notes on the data Data was downloaded from Yahoo finance, which includes the following features:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Classification Models</title>
      <link>https://niallmartin.io/posts/building-classification-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niallmartin.io/posts/building-classification-models/</guid>
      <description>Building Building on information presented in my previous post, this articles describes how bagging and boosted can be used to build a classification model. The data is available from Kaggle, and represents the financial transactions from two hundred thousand individuals (each with 800 features).
Using this dataset, I set about building a loan-default model. The overall pipeline for this project was split into a few stages, all of which are described below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>